Guide to the Donald Oliver/Chelsea Music Archive, 1907-2008 (bulk 1962-1991) MSS.254
Fales Library and Special Collections
Donald Oliver/Chelsea Music Archive
1907-2008
1962-1991
Fales Library and Special Collections
Oliver, Donald
MSS.254
71 Linear Feet in 48 records cartons and 20 oversize boxes
The Donald Oliver/Chelsea Music Archive consists of documents collected both personally by Donald Oliver and by Chelsea Music Services. Chelsea Music Services, Inc. was established as a "music factory of six or seven orchestrators willing to step in when needed." It became one of Broadway's favored music preparation services, producing "green-books," handwritten, and bound piano-conductor scores until 1988. The collection consists of librettos, piano-vocal scores, orchestrations, and video recordings pertaining to Broadway and Off-Broadway musicals. Among the prominent productions featured in the collection are A Chorus Line, The Phantom of the Opera, Breakfast at Tiffany's, and Merrily We Roll Along. The collection also documents the work of individual theater personalities, including actor Mandy Patinkin, performer Marti Stevens, and lyricist Dorothy Fields. Additional material includes playbills, newspaper clippings of reviews, screenplays and teleplays.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
The Donald Oliver/Chelsea Music Archive is arranged into five series, with additional oversize series for Series I and III listed at the end of the finding aid. All series are arranged alphabetically by production title or subject's last name.
The series are as follows:
Series I: Librettos and Playbills
Series II: Screenplays and Teleplays
Series III: Conductor Scores and Orchestrations
Series IV: Video Recordings
Series V: Paper Documentation from Video Recordings
Oversize Series I: Librettos and Playbills
Oversize Series III: Conductor Scores and Orchestrations
The titles of the librettos received in the 2016 accretion were integrated into Series I: Librettos and Playbills in alphabetical order, an arrangement scheme that had been adopted previously for the collection.
Biographical / Historical
After studying at the Manhattan School of Music and the BMI Musical Theatre Workshop under the direction of Lehman Engel, Donald Oliver served as the Artistic Director of Octagon Theatre Company in New York, an off-off-Broadway playhouse that produced musical revivals, including Zorba and Drat the Cat!. In 1978, Oliver began working with Chelsea Music Services, Inc., preparing music for numerous Broadway and Off-Broadway productions, his credits include Cats, Guys and Dolls, Kiss of the Spiderwoman, Into the Woods, and The Phantom of the Opera. In addition to his work at Chelsea Music Services, Oliver has also collaborated with lyricist Dan Butler in the production of The Case of the Dead Flamingo Dancer, first performed in 1986, and authored How to Audition for Musical Theatre: A Step-by-Step Guide to Effective Preparation (1995).
Founded by Don Walker and Mathilde Pincus, Chelsea Music Services, Inc. was established as a "music factory of six or seven orchestrators willing to step in when needed." Under Pincus's direction, Chelsea Music Services, Inc. became one of Broadway's favored music preparation services, producing "green-books," handwritten, bound piano-conductor scores, until Pincus's death in 1988. Spiral bound scores have been produced for more recent shows.
Sources:
Oliver, Donald, How to Audition for the Musical Theatre: A Step-by-Step Guide to Effective Preparation. Smith & Kraus Publishing, 1995.
Suskin, Steven, The Sound of Broadway Music: A Book of Orchestrators and Orchestrations. Oxford University Press, 2011.
Scope and Contents
The Donald Oliver/Chelsea Music Archive consists of documents collected both personally by Donald Oliver and by Chelsea Music Services, Inc. The collection consists of librettos, piano-vocal scores, orchestrations, and video recordings pertaining to Broadway and Off-Broadway musicals. Among the prominent productions featured in the collection are A Chorus Line, The Phantom of the Opera, Breakfast at Tiffany's, and Merrily We Roll Along. The collection also documents the work of individual theater personalities, including actor Mandy Patinkin, performer Marti Stevens, and lyricist Dorothy Fields. Additional material includes playbills, newspaper clippings of reviews, screenplays and teleplays.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated to NYU's Fales Library by Don Oliver in 2009. An accretion was later received in September 2016; the accession number associated with this gift is 2016.047.
Orchestral music -- Scores; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York -- Reviews; Off-Broadway theater; Librettos (documents for music); Musical theater -- New York (State) -- New York; Musical theater -- United States; Screenplays; Television scripts; Scores.; Patinkin, Mandy; Fields, Dorothy, 1905-1974; Stevens, Marti; Porter, Cole, 1891-1964
- Series I: Librettos and Playbills
  Scope and Content
  This series is comprised of original and photocopied librettos for Broadway and Off-Broadway productions. The bulk of this series consists of the librettos, which are in various stages of production, ranging from final versions, rehearsal, and draft copies. Many of the librettos include annotations and edits, which are noted in the finding aid. Also included in this series are playbills and newspaper clippings of theater reviews.
  - 13 Daughters, circa 1955-1962 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - 80 Days, April 1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Book by S[no]o Wilson Music and Lyrics by Ray Davies
  - 1491: A Romantic Speculation [Richard Morris draft], 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue: A Musical Play about the Problems of Housekeeping (Philadelphia Opening), February 26, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    Book and Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner Music by Leonard Bernstein
    contains marginalia
    handwritten note that this copy is from opening night in Philadelphia.
  - 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue: A Musical Play about the Problems of Housekeeping (Washington, D.C. Opening), March 24, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    handwritten note that this copy is from opening night in Washington DC
  - 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue: A Musical Play about the Problems of Housekeeping (New York Opening), May 4, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - A Chorus Line, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Chorus Line [revised], March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Book by James Kirkwood and Nicholas Dante Music by Marvin Hamlisch Lyrics by Edward Kleban
  - Actors and Actresses: A New Play [second draft], October 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    by Neil Simon
  - Aesop and Company: The Fabled Musical, November 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Book and lyrics by Jay Jeffries
  - After the Ball, [1954] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - All in Fun, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - All in Love: A New Musical Comedy, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Book and Lyrics by Bruce Geller Music by Jack Urbont
  - All the King's Horses, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Book and Lyrics by Frederick Herendeen Music by Edward Horan
  - The Almost Totally Fictitious Musical Hystery of Legs Diamond [revised], January 1, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Book by Harvey Fierstein and Charles Suppon Music and Lyrics by Peter Allen
  - Amateurs [rehearsal draft], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Book by Winnie Holzman and David Evans Music by David Evans Lyrics by Winnie Holzman
  - America's Sweetheart: A New Musical Comedy, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Fields, Rodgers and Hart
  - The Anastasia Game: A Musical Play, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Book by Jerome Chodorov and Guy Bolton Music and Lyrics by Robert Wright and George Forrest
  - Animal Crackers, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Book by George S. Kaufman and Morrie Ryskind Music and Lyrcis by Bert Kalmer and Harry Ruby
  - Ankles Aweigh: A Nautical Musical, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Book by Guy Bolton and Eddie Davis Music by Sammy Fain Lyrics by Dan Shapiro
  - Annie: A Play in Two Acts, January 6, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Book by Thomas Meehan Lyrics by Martin Charnin
  - Annie 2: Miss Hannigan's Revenge [rehearsal script, revised], December 12, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Book by Thomas Meehan Music by Charles Strouse Lyrics by Martin Charnin
  - Annie Get your Gun, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Book by Herbert and Dorothy Fields Music and Lyrics by Irving Berlin
  - Newspaper clipping, advertisement for "Anya", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Anything Goes: A Musical Comedy, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Book by Guy Bolton and P.G. Wodehouse (Revised by Howard Linsay and Russel Crouse) Music and Lyrics by Cole Porter
  - The Apprenticeship of Duddy Kravitz: A New Musical [first draft, revised], April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Book and Lyrics by David Spencer Music by Alan Menken
  - Arms and a Girl, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Around the World, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Around the World in 80 Days as a New Stage Musical in Two Acts [revised draft], 1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Book by Sig Herzig Music by Sammy Fain and Victor Young Lyrics by Harold Adamson
  - Arthur [third draft], June 3, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    by Steve Gordon
  - As Thousands Cheer, [1933] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - At Home Abroad, [1935] (Box 1, Folder 26)
    includes photocopy of original playbill
  - At Ravensdurn: A Comedy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    by Nick Hall
  - At the Grand, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Book by Luther Davis Music and Lyrics by Robert Wright and George Forrest
  - Aucassin and Nicolette: A Musical in Verse, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Book and Lyrics by Peter Kellogg
  - Awful Town: A Musical Spoof [in progress draft], 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Book and Lyrics by Gary Gardner Music by Robert Moreen
  - Babes in Arms: A Musical Show, [1937] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    By Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart
  - Baby: A Musical, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Book by Sybille Pearson Music by David Shire Lyrics by Richard Maltby, Jr.
  - Back on the Town: A New Musical Comedy Revue, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bajour: A New Musical Comedy, [1964] (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Book by Ernest Kinoy Music and Lyrics by Walter Marks
  - The Baker's Wife [working title]: A New Musical [2nd Draft], [1975] (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Book by Joseph Stein Music and Lyrics by Stephen Schwartz
  - The Baker's Wife, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Working copy (contains annotations)
  - Ballad for a Firing Squad: A Musical Play, Mata Hari [final revision], 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Book by Jerome Coopersmith Music by Edward Thomas Lyrics by Martin Charnin
  - The Band Wagon: A Revue, [1931] (Box 2, Folder 10)
    by George S. Kaufman and Howard Dietz Music by Arthur Schwartz
  - The Band Wagon: A Revue, [1931] (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Book by George S. Kaufman and Howard Dietz Music by Arthur Schwartz
  - Beg, Borrow or Steal: A Musical Comedy in Two Acts, [1960] (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Book by Bud Freeman Music by Leon Pober
  - Beggar's Holiday, [1946] (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Book and Lyrics by John La Touche Music by Duke Ellington
  - Le Bellybutton: A Sexy Musical, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    by Scott Mansfield
  - Best Foot Forward: A Musical Comedy, [1941] (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Book by John Cecil Holm Music and Lyrics by Hugh Martin and Ralph Blane
  - Betting on Bertie: A Musical Comedy, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Book by P.G. Wodehouse and Guy Bolton Music by Robert Wright and George Forrest
  - Between the Devil: A Musical Triangle in Two Acts, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    By Howard Dietz and Arthue Schwartz
  - [Big: The Musical], [1995] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Billion Dollar Baby, [1945] (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Book and Lyrics by Betty Comden and Adolph Green Music by Morton Gould
  - Billy Rose's Crazy Quilt, [1931] (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bless You All, December 14, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Music by Harold Rome Sketches by Arnold Auerbach
  - Blitz!: A New Musical, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Book by Lionel Bart and Joan Maitland Music and Lyrics by Lionel Bart
  - Bloomer Girl: A Modern Musical Comedy with Old-Fashioned Charm, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Book by Sig Herzig and Fred Saidy Music by Harold Arlen Lyrics by E.Y. Harburg Based on a play by Dan and Lilith James
  - Blossom Time [stage guide], undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Book and Lyrics by Dorothy Donnelly Music by Franz Schubert and Heinrich Berte
  - La Boheme [final draft], 1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Book and Lyrics by David Spencer Music by Giacomo Puccini
  - Bohemians: A New English Version of the Opera "La Boheme", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    original date of Oct. 6, 1983 is crossed out and May 15, 1984 is handwritten below it. Version A, second draft
  - Bonanza Bound!: A Musical Comedy About the Alaskan Gold Rush of 1898, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Book and Lyrics by Betty Comden and Adolph Green Music by Saul Chaplin
  - Booth is Back in Town: A Musical, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Book by Austin Pendelton Music by Arthur Rubinstein Lyrics by Gretchen Cryer
  - The Boys from Syracuse, [1938] (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Book by George Abbott Music by Richard Rodgers Lyrics by Lorenz Hart
  - El Bravo: A Musical Comedy Fable, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Book by Jose Fernandez and Thom Schiera Music and Lyrics by John Clifton
    Rehearsal draft
  - Breakfast at Tiffany's, [1966] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Breakfast at Tiffany's, December 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Book by Edward Albee Music and Lyrics by Bob Merrill
  - Breakfast at Tiffany's [2nd rehearsal version], [1966] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Breakfast at Tiffany's playbill, Majestic Theatre, [1966] (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Adaptation by Edward Albee Music and Lyrics by Bob Merrill
  - A Broadway Musical, November 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Book by William F. Brown Music by Charles Strouse Lyrics by Lee Adams
  - A Broadway Musical supplemental materials, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - By the Beautiful Sea, [1954] (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Book by Herbert and Dorothy Fields Music by Arthur Schwartz Lyrics by Dorothy Fields
  - By Jupiter, [1942] (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Book by Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart Music by Richard Rodgers Lyrics by Lorenz Hart
  - Bye Bye Birdie, [1960] (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Book by Mike Stewart Music by Charles Strouse Lyrics by Lee AdamsMiss Saigon
    Fourth draft
  - Cabin In The Sky, undated (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - La Cage aux Folles: The Broadway Musical [revised edition], April 7, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Book by Harvey Fierstein Music and Lyrics by Jerry Herman
  - La Cage aux Folles: The Broadway Musical [revised], December 1, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Call Me Madam, [1950] (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Book by Howard Lindsay and Russel Crouse Music and Lyrics by Irving Berlin
  - Call Me Mister: A Musical Revue, [1946] (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Music and Lyrics by Harold Rome Sketches by Arnold Auerbach
  - Can-Can, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Book by Abe Burrows Music and Lyrics by Cole Porter
  - Candide [playing version], January 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Book by Hugh Wheeler Music by Leonard Bernstein Lyrics by Richard Wilbur
  - Captain America, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Book by Mel Mandel, Philip Rose and Norman Sachs Music by Norman Sachs Lyrics by Mel Mandel
  - Captains Courageous: A Musical, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Book and Lyrics by Patrick Cook Music by Frederick Freyer
  - Carmelina: A Musical Play, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Book by Alan Jay Lerner and Joseph Stein Music by Burton Lane Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner
  - Carrie, [1988] (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Book by Lawrence D. Cohen Music by Michael Gore Lyrics by Dean Pitchford
  - The Case of the Dead Flamingo Dancer (A Nick Lambent Tap-Fable-Mystery): A Play with Dance, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    by Dan Butler
  - The Cat and the Fiddle: A Musical Love Story, [1931] (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Book by Otto Harback Music by Jerome Kern
  - The Cat and the Fiddle: A Musical Love Story, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Catherine [Was Great], [1944] (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Cats: A Musical, October 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Music by Andrew Lloyd Webber
  - C.C. Pyle and the Bunion Derby, undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Champagne, Sec: An Operetta, [1933] (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Music by Johann Strauss Book adapted by Lawrence Langner Lyrics adapted by Robert A. Simon
  - Chaplin, July 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    By Anthony Newley and Stanley Ralph Ross
    Includes newspaper clippings
  - Chee-Chee!: A Musical Narrative, [1928] (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Book by Lew M. Fields Music by Richard Rodgers Lyrics by Lorenz Hart
  - Chess: A New Musical [American revision], January 25, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Book by Tim Rice and Richard Nelson Music by Benny Andersson and Bjorn Ulvaeus Lyrics by Tim Rice
  - Chicago: a musical vaudeville [rehearsal script], October 21, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Book by Fred Ebb and Bob Fosse Music by John Kander Lyrics by Fred Ebb
  - Chin-Chin: Musical Extravaganza in Three Acts, [1914] (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Book by Ann Caldwell and R.H. Burnside Music by Ivan Caryll
  - Chorus Girls on Mars!, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    by James C. Kantor
  - Christy: A Musical Adaptation of The Playboy of the Western World, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Book and Lyrics by Bernie Spiro Music by Lawrence J. Blank
  - Chu-Chem [rehearsal script 2], October 25, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Book by Ted Allan Music by Mitch Leigh Lyrics by Jim Haines and Jack Wohl
  - Coco: A Musical Play [office file copy], December 18, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Book and Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner Music by Andre Previn
  - The Cocoanuts: A Musical Comedy in Two Acts, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Book by George S. Kaufman Music and Lyrics by Irving Berlin
  - The Cocoanuts: A Musical Comedy in Two Acts, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Colette: A Musical, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Book and Lyrics by Tom Jones Music by Harvey Schmidt
  - Colette, October 1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Adapted by Elinor Jones from "Earthly Paradise" by Robert Phelps
  - Colombe: A Musical based on "Mademoiselle Colombe" [first rough draft], undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    by Jean Anouilh Book by Caryl Brahms, New Sherrin & Tony Glass Music by Michael Valenti Lyrics by Edwin Dulchin
  - Come Summer, June 1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Book and lyrics by Will Holt Music by David Baker
    Based on "Rainbow on the Road" by Esther Forbes
  - Company: A Musical Comedy, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Book by George Furth Music and Lyrics by Stephen Sondheim
  - A Connecticut Yankee, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Book by Herbert Fields Music by Richard Rodgers Lyrics by Lorenz Hart
  - A Connecticut Yankee [new revised version], undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - A Connecticut Yankee [new revised version], 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Constant Sinner, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    By Mae West
  - Cool Off!: A Musical Play, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Book by Jerome Weidman Music and Lyrics by Howard Blankman
  - [The Corn is Green]: A Musical Play, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Book by Emlyn Williams and Joshua Logan Music by Albert Hague Lyrics by Emlyn Williams
  - Cranks, November 26, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Book by John Cranko Music by John Addison
  - Crazy for You: The Touching Story of a Man, a Woman, and the Same Man (fourth draft), August 13, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Book by Ken Ludwig Music by George Gershwin Lyrics by Ira Gershwin
  - Crazy for You: The Touching Story of a Man, a Woman, and the Same Man (New York production draft), April 20, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Curtains: A New Musical (second draft), [2007] (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Booky by Peter Stone Music by John Kander Lyrics by Fred Ebb
  - Dance a Little Closer: A New Musical (revised edition), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Book and Lyrics by Alan Jay Lerner Music by Charles Strouse
  - Dance Me A Song: A New Musical Revue, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Songs, except where noted, by James Shelton
  - Dance of the Vampires: A Musical (May 1 Script), May 1, [2002] (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Book by David Ives, Jim Steinman and Michael Kunza Music and Lyrics by Jim Steinman
  - Dance of the Vampires: A Musical (Aug. 16 script), August 16, [2002] (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Book by David Ives, Jim Steinman, and Michael Kunze Music and Lyrics by Jim Steinman
  - Dancin', 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Recreated by Gail Benedict
  - Dancing in the Streets, April 20, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Day Before Spring, [1945] (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Book by Alan J. Lerner
  - A Day in Hollywood, A Night in the Ukraine, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Book and Lyrics by Dick Vosburgh Music by Frank Lazarus
  - Dear Sir, [1924] (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Book by Edgar Selwyn Music by Jerome Kern Lyrics by Howard Dietz
  - Dear World: A New Musical [early version], June 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Music and lyrics by Jerry Herman Book by Jerome Lawrence and Robert E. Lee
  - Dear World: A New Musical [rehearsal draft], 1968 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Book by Jerome Lawrence and Robert E. Lee Music and Lyrics by Jerry Herman
  - Dear World: A New Musical [opening night version], 1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dearest Enemy, [1925] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    by Herbert Fields
  - Destry Rides Again, [1959] (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Music and lyrics by Harold Rome Book by Leonard Gershe
  - Diamond Lil, [April] 1928 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Produced by Jack Linder Starred Mae West
  - Diamond Lil, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    By Mark Linder and May West
  - Do Re Mi, [1960] (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Book by Garson Kanin Music by Jule Styne Lyrics by Betty Comden and Adolph Green
  - A Doll's Life, [1982] (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Book and Lyrics by Betty Comden and Adolph Green Music by Larry Grossman
  - A Doll's Life, [1982] (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Donnybrook!, [1961] (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Book by Robert E. McEnroe Music and Lyrics by Johnny Burke
  - Drat The Cat, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Drat! The Cat!: A New Musical Comedy (revised), and revision pages, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Book and Lyrics by Ira Levin Music by Milton Schafer
  - Dreamgirls, 1983 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - DuBarry Was A Lady, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Eight to the Bar, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Book by Stephen Witkin Music and Lyrics by Joey Miller
  - Eleanor, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Elmer-Gantry: A Musical, [1969] (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Book by Peter Bellwood Music by [Stanley] Lyrics by Fred Tobias
    Rehearsal script contains marginalia
  - Ernest in Love, undated (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - The Escort, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    by John Wolfson
  - Family Affair: A Wedding in Two Acts, [1962] (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Book by James and William Goldman Music by John Kander Lyrics by James Goldman and John Kander
  - A Few More Years, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    by Oliver Hailey
  - Fifty Million Frenchmen, undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - The Fig Leaves are Falling: A Musical Comedy (revised), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Book and Lyrics by Allan Sherman Music by Albert Hague
  - Fine and Dandy: A Musical Comedy, [1930] (Box 6, Folder 3)
    By Donald Ogden Stewart
  - The Firefly, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Music by Rudolf Friml Book and lyrics by Otto Harbach
  - The Five O'clock Girl, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Book by Guy Bolton and Fred Thompson Music and Lyrics by Bert Kalmar and Harry Ruby
  - Flahooley, [1951] (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Book by Fred Saidy and E. Y. Harburg Lyrics by E. Y. Harburg Music by Sammy Fain and Burton Lane
    Contains annotations
  - Flahooley, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Flahooley, undated (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Flora, The Red Menace, 1965 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Florodora, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Book by Owen Hall Music by Leslie Stuart Lyrics by E. Boyd Jomes and Paul Rubens
  - Flowers for Algernon, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)